# VAN THIEU NGUYEN

Software Engineer



# **Contact Information**

- May 07, 1997
- Male
- A Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam
- 0363091909
- in vanthieu-nguyen
- Curriculum Vitae on Web

# **Skills**

### **Technical Skills**

- ✓ Javascript/Typescript
- ✔ React/Next
- ✔ Redux(Redux Thunk, Redux Toolkit)
- ✓ Ant Design/Material UI
- ✓ CSS/SCSS/Responsive
- ✓ Styled JSX/Styled Component
- ✓ Jest/Cypress
- ✓ Node/Electron

#### Soft Skills

- ✓ Teamwork
- ✓ Time management
- ✓ Communication
- ✓ Problem solving

# **Objective**

As a consistent, hard-working, highly motivated person, I am looking forward to participating as a team member in a dynamic work environment which provides an opportunity to make a strong contribution by utilizing and expanding upon related education, skills, experiences, and capabilities.

# Work experience

## **Frontend Developer**

Mar 2022 - Present

#### Shopback

- Maintain, revamp UI/UX and implement new features(table listing, form validation, image validation) in Admin Panel page for ten countries.
- Research and apply micro frontend for company's web platform.

### **Frontend Developer**

Jan 2020 - Mar 2022

#### **Shopee**

- Build many services to serve local Vietnam operations, such as Game Admin, Warehouse, Flash Sale, Seller Rewards,... (Single SPA, React, Redux, Ant).
- Build landing page website for Seller Rewards program (Next, React, Redux, Responsive).
- Research and build a cross-platform desktop app that supports Windows/macOS. Shopee operators can create a carousel banner, a campaign calendar, a drawing tool,... (Electron, React, Redux, Ant, React Final Form).
- Build game "Số gì đây?": Create an admin page on Shopee Desktop App to set up data and images, import attendees, Handle logic to randomize the winner based on certain criteria (React, Redux, Ant, Broadcast Channel API).
- Research and write integration testing (Cypress).
- Suggestions to improve UI to make the product better.
- Organize technical sharing for team members: Sharing about EletronJS and Cypress. Get Shopee reward in Happy Trainers Day.

#### Language

Vietnamese, English

### **Interests**

- Read books and learn about the purpose of life.
- Relax with instrumental music.
- Traveled somewhere nearby HCM city at the weekend.

### **Javascript Developer**

May 2019 - Dec 2019

#### Gameloft

- Design interface for the tool on the website using Javascript (Nodejs, React, Redux, Material UI).
- Programming mini-game on Spark AR tool (effect on Facebook and Instagram) (Javascript, Spark AR Tool).
- Optimize, fix bugs and implement new features in old projects.

# Game Evolution Programmer

Sep 2018 - May 2019

### Gameloft

- Check and fix bugs in the game Dragon Mania Legend (C++, Java).
- Implement new features in this game.

#### Freelancer

Sep 2018 - Present

Upwork / Freelancer

- Revamp UI, fix issue of my client's website.
- Develop WordPress website base on figma design.
- Develop Reactis/MERN projects.
- Learn more knowledge based on the work I was assigned.

### **Education**

Ho Chi Minh city University of Sep 2015 - Nov 2019 **Technology** 

Major: Control Engineering & Automation

GPA: 8.54/10

# **Honors & Awards**

2017-2019: Panasonic Scholarship

@vanthieunguyen